the rename refactoring in IntelliJ IDEA
IntelliJ IDEA中的重命名重构
is probably the simplest type of a
可能是最简单的类型
factoring that you can perform but for
可以执行的因素，但对于
such a simple refactoring it has a lot
如此简单的重构有很多
of neat functionality that goes on
的功能不断完善
behind the scenes and so first let's
在幕后，所以首先让我们
describe what this or factoring does
描述这或保理的作用
whenever you rename a variable or a
每当您重命名变量或
class or any type of field inside your
类或您内部的任何类型的字段
code then IntelliJ IDEA will rename all
代码，然后IntelliJ IDEA将重命名所有
references to that field immediately
立即引用该字段
now this refactoring may seem very
现在这种重构似乎非常
simple at first glance but it really
乍一看很简单，但实际上
involves three steps as you may be aware
您可能知道，涉及三个步骤
IntelliJ IDEA indexes all of the symbols
IntelliJ IDEA索引所有符号
inside your editor and so whenever you
在您的编辑器中，因此无论何时您
click on one of these symbols it will
单击这些符号之一，它将
link to another symbol you can do this
链接到另一个符号，您可以执行此操作
within your own code and to an external
在您自己的代码中，并在外部
code base as well which will be
代码库也将是
decompiled for you this is all
为您反编译，这就是全部
accomplished through a simple index
通过简单的索引完成
whenever you navigate to the definition
每当您导航到定义时
for a symbol inside your editor then
在编辑器中输入一个符号
IntelliJ IDEA will look up the location
IntelliJ IDEA将查找位置
of where that symbol is being defined
该符号的定义位置
and take you directly there now there's
然后直接带你去那里
also something called an inverted index
也叫倒排索引
where if you click on a variable or a
如果您点击变量或
symbol inside your editor and press alt
编辑器中的符号，然后按alt
f7 then the IDE will return an inverted
f7则IDE将返回反向
index where the key is the name of the
索引，其中键是名称
symbol you're looking for and the values
您正在寻找的符号和值
are all of the occurrences of that
是所有的发生
symbol all of its usages inside your
象征您内部的所有用法
entire project
整个项目
so whenever rename something inside our
所以每当在我们内部重命名
editor three things need to happen if we
编辑器，如果我们需要做三件事
rename a variable inside a method then
重命名方法中的变量，然后
we can just get away with renaming all
我们可以重命名所有内容
usages of that variable and calling it a
该变量的用法并将其称为
day our job is done if we were named a
如果我们被命名为
field then we'll need to rename the name
字段，那么我们需要重命名名称
of the variable itself and any usages
变量本身及其任何用法
where it occurs but also potentially the
它发生的地方，但也有可能
name of the getter and setter as well
获取器和设置器的名称
and then maybe any constructor
然后可能是任何构造函数
parameters that are assigned to it in
分配给它的参数
order to be consistent finally if we
如果我们最终能够保持一致
change the name of a type such as here
更改类型的名称，例如这里
in enum then we'll need to do all of
在枚举中，那么我们需要做所有
that
那
in addition to any parameters fields and
除了任何参数字段和
possibly method names as well so the
可能还有方法名称，所以
goal here really isn't just to find and
我们的目标不只是寻找和
replace the end result needs to be
替换最终结果需要
readable and by using this rename
可读并使用此重命名
refactoring you can accomplish all three
重构就可以完成全部三个
thanks for watching
谢谢收看